

# Michael Bieri

Grotweg 23
2543 Lengnau BE
+41 77 413 08 39
michael.bieri@hotmail.com
13.03.1992







### Work Experience

07/2024 - 10/2024	Career transition Relocation, travel and continuing education
03/2021 - 06/2024	Product Engineer Electronics LAUFEN Bathrooms AG, Laufen Development and management of soft- and hardware projects with focus on requirement engineering
09/2018 - 02/2021	Junior Project Manager Amstein + Walthert Basel AG, Basel Engineering in building technology/automation
07/2018 - 09/2018	Internship Environmental Engineer Kappeler Infra Consult AG, Laufen
11/2013 - 07/2014	Workshop and Construction Internship F. Hoffmann-La-Roche AG, Basel
11/2010 - 05/2011	Trust Internship TVR Treuhand GmbH, Basel
09/2009 - 10/2009	Bank Internship WIR Bank, Basel

## About Me

With over three years of experience in the development of innovative IoT, data and digitalisation solutions, I have extensive expertise.

I have knowledge in classic and agile project management methods, requirements engineering techniques as well as programming and IT skills to successfully implement challenging projects. I attach great importance to developing myself further together with the company in order to realise innovative products.

#### Skills

REQUIREMENT ENGINEERING



\_\_\_\_\_

ANALYTICAL THINKING

STATISTICS

DATA SCIENCE

**DATA ANALYSIS** 



- Professional Scrum Master II
- Databricks Certified Data Engineer Associate
- Microsoft Fundamentals in Azure, Power Platform, MS365



#### Education

02/2024 - 08/2024	<b>CAS Data Science Fundamentals</b> Swiss Distance University of Applied Sciences FFHS
09/2019 - 04/2022	MAS Automation Management University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
09/2014 - 05/2018	BSc Energy- and Environment Technology University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
08/2011 - 08/2012	Technical High School Diploma Vocational training center BL
08/2007 - 08/2010	Business Diploma Business school kvBL

Α×

#### Languages

German Mother tongue

English C1

French B2